Sumo...
（ナレーション）“相撲”…
土俵上で 廻(まわ)しのみを身につけ 戦う
日本古来の武道であり—
Battles waged in a ring by those wearing
mawashi belts since ancient times in Japan.
It is one of the few combat sports
without weight classes.
数少ない“無差別級”の格闘技
Thus, larger and heavier student sumo
wrestlers have a distinct advantage.
ゆえに 学生相撲においても—
“大きく”“重く”ある者が
絶対優位
中でも
横綱候補と期待される者には…
Among them...
Those with the potential to
reach the rank of yokozuna...
receive the name of a sword from the
national treasures as their moniker.
国宝級の刀剣に なぞらえた—
二つ名が与えられた
Odachi High School
Sumo Club
（小関）ウワッ！
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）ンンッ！
Ow...
いってて…
やっぱり潮(うしお)には かなわないな
I'm still no match for you, Ushio.
You've put a lot of work
into the basics, Captain.
部長は コツコツと
基礎練をやってきただけあって—
足腰は強いんじゃがな
It's made your legs
and loins really strong.
I can't believe I get to
do sumo in the dojo again.
また ここで相撲を取れるなんて…
The delinquents had been
using it as their hangout,
不良たちの
たまり場だった部室を—
この小さな新入部員が—
before this tiny new club member
wrested it back single-handedly.
たったひとりで
取り返してくれたんだ
あ〜 早く試合がしたいのぅ！
Man, I really want to compete in a real bout!
Hey, Captain, when's the next tournament?
部長
次の大会は いつだったかのぅ？
A real bout? We still only have
a grand total of two members.
試合って…　まだ僕ら
２人しか部員がいないんだよ
We need at least three more
to enter a tournament.
団体戦に出るためには
最低でも あと３人入ってこないと
No need to worry!
それなら心配いらん
Tomorrow is club sign-up day,
so we'll get hordes of new members!
あしたの部活動発表会で
たくさん入るからのぅ
What makes you so sure that'll happen?
（小関）どこから
その自信が湧いてくるんだよ？
大丈夫じゃ　ワシに策がある
It's all good, man. I've got a plan.
（小関）策？
A plan?
相撲といえば ちゃんこ鍋
Sumo and chankonabe stew go hand in hand!
The Great
Chanko
Stew Plan
We'll use this delicious stew
to rope in loads of new members!
ちゃんこ屋で 人を集めて
新入部員確保大作戦じゃ！
Bout 2
"Wrestling vs Sumo"
（佑真(ゆうま)）
ハァハァ…　くそ！
Damn!
What the hell are you?!
何なんだよ？　てめえは
（不良１）
随分と うなされてたようだな
You were wailin' in your sleep.
Havin' nightmares about gettin'
beaten up by a freshman?
（不良２）
新入生に やられてる夢でも
見てたんじゃねえのか
（佑真）ああ？
（不良２）ウッ…
That kid...
あいつ…
ワシは 相撲で日本一になるんじゃ
I'm going to be the best
sumo wrestler in Japan.
You're welcome to challenge me
in the ring any time.
土俵の上なら
いつでも受けて立つぞ
フン…
なにが日本一だよ　バカらしい！
The best in Japan? What a joke.
Come experience the sweat of adolescence!
（サッカー部員）俺たちと一緒に
青春の汗を流さないか？
The tennis club is having
a game of target practice!
（テニス部員）テニスで
的当てゲームやってま〜す！
Why don't you try sumo?
相撲 始めてみんか？
Welcome to
the Sumo Club
No experience necessary!
未経験でも大丈夫！
Delicious
Chankonabe Stew
（小関）ハァ…
It's hard to get high schoolers
interested in sumo these days.
やっぱ 今どきの高校生には
相撲って ハードル高いよな…
It's all good, man.
大丈夫じゃ
We have this in our corner!
こっちには これがある　オッ…
Hey, you guys!
そこのあんたら　ちょいと
ちゃんこだけでも食べていかんか？
Why not at least try a bowl of chanko stew?
（生徒）へえ…
ちゃんこって食べたことないや
I've never had chanko stew before.
（生徒）
ま… まずっ！　何だ！？　この味
I-It's awful! What's in this?!
B-But it can't be...
（火ノ丸）そ… そんなはずは…
Don't feed people this junk!
（生徒）
変な物 食べさせやがって！
What did you put in this
to make it taste so bad?!
なに入れたら
こんな味になるんだよ！？
I wanted it to be nutritious, so I added
some garlic and protein powder.
（火ノ丸）
いや 栄養とか考えて—
ニンニクとかプロテインとか…
（においを嗅ぐ音）
ちょ… ちょっと
人のにぎわってるとこで—
I-I'll go find a crowd
and start handing out flyers.
勧誘のビラ配ってくるよ
Was it really that bad?
そんなに ひどい味だったかのぅ…
（千比路(ちひろ)）ウ〜ン…　デリシャス
（火ノ丸）あっ…
Mm, delicious.
（飲み込む音）
（千比路）ハァ〜ッ…
この独特の苦みと うまみが
あとを引くぜ
Its unique bitterness and depth of flavor
make you sit up and take notice!
Oh, you like it?
おお〜！　そうか うまいか
遠慮せず どんどん食っとくれ
Have as much as you want!
オッ…　いいのか？
じゃ 遠慮なく
Are you sure?
Don't mind if I do!
You look pretty strong.
あんた 強そうじゃのぅ
どうじゃ？　相撲に興味はないか？
Are you interested in sumo?
Huh? Sumo?
うん？　相撲か…
I do want to boost my prospects
by doing lots of combat sports,
将来のために いろいろと
経験はしておきてえが—
相撲は あんまり興味ねえな
but sumo doesn't really interest me.
Your prospects?
将来？
I'm Kunisaki Chihiro, a second-year.
俺は ２年の國崎(くにさき)千比路
レスリング部だ
I'm in the wrestling club.
I'm gonna become America's
top mixed martial arts fighter!
いずれアメリカで
総合格闘技界の頂点を取る男よ
おお！　ならばワシは
大相撲の頂点 横綱になる男
Well, I'm gonna be a top
pro sumo wrestler: a yokozuna!
I'm Ushio Hinomaru!
（火ノ丸）潮火ノ丸じゃ
（千比路）うん？
Hold up.
おっと…
俺に合わせた冗談なら笑えねえな
That kind of joke isn't gonna
get a laugh outta me.
I was being deadly serious when I said that.
俺はマジで目指してっから 頂点
Joke?
（火ノ丸）冗談じゃと？
I'm serious, too.
ワシだって本気じゃ
I get the feeling we're two of a kind.
お前からは
俺と同じものを感じるぜ
Like, we smell the same or something.
何つうの？
においっつうか何つうか…
あっ そうだ　これやるよ
気に入ったヤツには渡してんだ
Oh, you can have this.
I'm giving these to
people I find interesting.
Dachi High
Exhibition Match
Special Invitation
It combines attracting new members
and training in glorious fashion.
新入生の勧誘と 俺の修行を兼ねて
派手にやるからよ
O-Okay.
（火ノ丸）お… おう
Come by if you're up for it.
気が向いたら見に来てくれ
じゃあな
See ya.
Chihiro, huh?
千比路か…
なかなか面白そうなヤツじゃ
He's an interesting guy.
But he's not interested in sumo.
…が 相撲は興味ないか
After volleyball, the wrestling club
is holding an exhibition match.
（生徒会役員１）バレー部の次は
レスリング部が行う—
エキシビションマッチです
We're behind schedule.
（礼奈(れいな)）
少しスケジュールが遅れ気味ね
Get everyone to step on it.
（礼奈）全体の進行を早めなさい
（役員たち）はい！
Yes, ma'am!
Dude. That girl's a real knockout!
（生徒）なあ
あの子 すっげえ かわいくない？
（生徒）
うん？　お前　知らないのか？
You don't know her?
That's last year's Miss Dachi High
あの人は 去年のミス･ダチ高にして
現生徒会会長の礼奈さんだぞ！
and current student council president,
Reina-san!
（生徒）えっ？　あの人が？
That's her?!
（礼奈）フフフッ…　早くも
新入生たちが 私に注目してるわね
The freshmen are already
taking notice of me.
Still, it's running very smoothly this year.
（生徒会役員２）いやぁ
それにしても 今年は平和ですね
It must be because that new guy in the
sumo club took care of all the delinquents—
相撲部の新入生が 不良たちを
おとなしくしてくれたおかげ…
（生徒会役員３）バカ！　お前…
Hey, doofus! Shut up!
Don't mention that in front of Reina-san!
（生徒会役員１）
礼奈さんの前で それは禁句！
（うなり声）
（役員たち）ヒイ〜ッ！
どう？　ちゃんこ屋は
How's our chanko stew stand doing?
It's just how it looks. No one's turned up.
見てのとおり 全然じゃ　部長は？
How about you, Captain?
ビラは配ってきたけど
反応はイマイチだったよ
I handed out flyers, but no one
seemed remotely interested.
I see.
そうか…　あっ…
Actually, an interesting guy
came by and gave me this.
そういえば 面白いヤツが来て
こんな物をくれたぞ
Delicious
Chankonabe Stew
Strong
and
Manly
Delicious
Cheap
Irresistible
A Taste
of Sumo
Ah, this event.
（小関）あ〜 このイベント
さっき 体育館に
人がいっぱい集まってたよ
Yeah, a bunch of people were
milling around in the gym for it.
（火ノ丸）へえ…　羨ましいのぅ
Aw man, I'm jealous.
よし…　ここにいても人は来ないし
俺らも行ってみよう
Well, no one's coming over
to our stand, so let's go watch.
Supreme! Invincible! The strongest!
（千比路）究極！　無敵！
（千比路）最強〜！
（司会）一本！
Ippon!
That was his arm drag finishing move:
the Chihiro Special #1!
（司会）必殺の巻き投げ
“チヒロスペシャル１号”
Hot on the heels of defeats for the karate
and boxing clubs, the judo club falls!
空手部 ボクシング部に続き—
柔道部でも歯が立たず！
（千比路の雄たけび）
（火ノ丸）ほう…
千比路のヤツ すげえじゃねえの
Chihiro's really good.
O-Of course he is.
（小関）そ… そりゃそうだよ
He was national champ last year.
去年の国体で
日本一になった選手だもの
So this guy's the strongest
at Dachi High, not Yuma?
ダチ高最強は 佑真じゃなくて
あいつなんじゃねえのか？
う… う〜ん それは…
W-Well...
Wait! What's this?
（司会）
お〜っと！　これは いけない
The champion's telling the
loser where he went wrong!
チャンピオンによる
敗者へのダメ出しが始まったぞ！
（千比路）ポンだろう！
He's known as Dachi High's Mr. Untouchable.
（小関）通称
“ダチ高のアンタッチャブル”
He can be really obnoxious
if you get mixed up with him.
関わると 何かと面倒くさくて…
It's still a combat sport.
しかし 異種格闘技戦か…
It really captures everyone's imagination.
なかなか どうして
注目度は抜群じゃ！
Wrestling's awesome.
He's in the wrestling club?
（司会）さあ 次の挑戦者は誰だ！
（千比路）うん？
Okay, who's the next challenger?
Oh! Next in the ring is...
（司会）
おっと 次は す… 相撲部？
...th-the sumo club?
（礼奈）相撲部？
The sumo club?
Hey, I've been waiting for you, Hinomaru.
（千比路）
よう　待ってたぜ　火ノ丸
Sumo doesn't speak to me, but you,
on the other hand, are an interesting fella.
相撲には興味ねえが お前には
少し興味があったんだよな
H-Hey, Ushio...
お… おい 潮
Isn't it sad, Captain? Everyone says
they're not interested in sumo.
悲しいのぅ 部長
みんな 相撲には興味ねえってよ
I guess they'll have to see it up close
やっぱ実際に見てもらわねえと
伝わんねえよな
相撲の魅力ってやつはよ
to understand just how great sumo is!
ほう…
（生徒）おい 聞いたか？
（佑真）うん？
Hey, did you hear?
That freshman from the sumo club is taking
on Kunisaki from the wrestling club.
（生徒）相撲部の１年が
レスリング部の國崎と戦うらしいぜ
Wh-What? Really?
（生徒）えっ？　マジで？
そいつって あの佑真さんに…
The guy who beat Yuma-san?
Yeah. Back when Yuma-san was considered
the strongest guy at Dachi High.
（生徒）そう
元ダチ高最強の佑真さんに勝った…
ヒイッ…
チッ！
あいつ なに考えてやがる…
What the hell is that shrimp thinking?
（火ノ丸）
何より あんたに見てほしい
I want you to see this up close, Chihiro.
いちばん近くでな　千比路！
あ〜 誘っといて何だけどよ
相撲ってのは神事だろう？
I realize I invited you to this event,
but sumo's big on rituals, isn't it?
You sure you're allowed
to do it in any old hall?
いいのか？
こんな俗っぽい所でやって
Professional sumo wrestling is
part-ritual, part-entertainment.
（火ノ丸）
大相撲には 神事としての側面と
興行としての側面がある
I'm gonna have to entertain a Kokugikan Arena
that's packed to the rafters one day,
いずれ 満席の国技館(こくぎかん)で
相撲を取る身としては—
so this will be good practice.
いい予行演習じゃ
ハハハハッ！
やる気フルマックスってわけだ
You're really up for this, aren't ya?
H-Hey...
（小関）お… おい
Are you sure about this, Ushio?
ホントにいいのか？　潮
Sure, beating the national wrestling champ
would make the sumo club look good, but...
そりゃ レスリング
国体チャンピオンに勝てば—
相撲部のアピールにはなるけど…
If I lose, I'm sorry.
（火ノ丸）もし負けたら すまん
（小関）えっ？
Of course, making sumo
look good is part of it,
確かに
いちばんの目的は それじゃが—
but this is a rare chance to
face a top-class athlete.
こんな最上級のアスリートと
まみえる機会は そうはねえ
ワシが もっと強くなるために
こいつと戦ってみたいんじゃ
I want to fight him to get stronger.
潮…
Ushio...
Besides, wrestling matches are
bare-handed fights in a ring.
（火ノ丸）
それに レスリングってよ
円形のリングの上 素手で組み合う
It's really similar to sumo.
どこか相撲に似てるとは思わんか？
チッチッチッ…　全然 違(ちげ)えよ
They're completely different.
With throws in judo and pinfalls in wrestling,
they leave you vulnerable to a fatal blow.
柔道の一本や
レスリングのピンフォールは—
次の一手で死が待ってる
いわば 詰みの状態だ
You're completely defenseless.
Then, you look at sumo.
だが 相撲は どうだ？
If you leave the ring, you lose.
土俵の外に出たら負け
地面に手をついたら負け
If your hand touches the ground, you lose.
Why? They could just keep fighting.
なんで？　まだ戦えるじゃん
The way I see it, a loss
in sumo has less meaning.
俺に言わせりゃ
負けの重みが違うね
You can't call it a victory unless
you completely subdue your opponent.
相手を
完全に制圧してこその勝利だろう
I'm going to be a mixed martial artist,
いずれ
総合格闘技に進む俺には—
so sumo just seems a little wimpy to me.
相撲ってのは
どうにも ぬるいんだよな
Wimpy, huh?
ぬるいか…　なら こうしよう
I have a suggestion.
You fight under wrestling rules,
and I'll fight under sumo rules.
あんたはレスリングをやり
ワシは相撲をやる
If I set foot outside this circle,
（火ノ丸）ワシは
このサークルの外に出たり—
or touch the ground with anything
other than the soles of my feet, I lose.
足の裏以外が地面についたら負け
You lose if you're on your
back for more than one second.
千比路は 背中が
地面に１秒以上ついたら負け
Don't worry about your hands
or knees touching the ground.
いくら手や膝をついても かまわん
（司会）な… なんと 相撲部
What's the sumo club doing?
自らが 圧倒的に
不利になる条件を提示してきた！
He's just given his
opponent a huge advantage!
This guy...
あいつ…
Is he an idiot?
バカなんじゃないの？
あっ…
そうだ いいこと思いついちゃった
I've just had a brainwave.
I don't think you're doing this
'cause you're underestimating me.
俺をナメてるわけじゃなさそうだな
いいぜ
Okay, but I have my own pride to consider.
だが 俺にだってプライドがある
（柔道部員）うん？　イヤ〜ン！
There we go. Now, it'll be
easier to grab me, right?
さあ これで
つかみやすくなっただろう？
Yeah.
It's getting increasingly
electric in this gymnasium.
（司会）会場のボルテージも
高まってまいりましたね
What's your take on it, Ozeki-san?
（司会）解説の小関さん
（小関）えっ？　か… 解説？
Huh? M-My take?
Wh-What's this?
な… なんと…
The guest referee who
will officiate this fight
この戦いを裁く特別レフェリーは
生徒会長の礼奈さんだ！
will be none other than student
council president Reina-san!
Thank you, everyone!
皆さん　よろしく！
な… なんで あいつが…
Wh-What's she doing out there?
Do you even know the rules?
（千比路）あんたに できるのか？
（火ノ丸）ワシは かまわんが…
I don't mind her refereeing.
This guy beat Yuma?
（礼奈）
こんなヤツに 佑真が負けた？
I don't know how he did it,
but I don't accept it.
どんな手を使ったのか知らないけど
認めないんだから
（司会）
さあ まもなく レスリング対相撲
Very soon, wrestling vs sumo, the combat
sports battle of the century will begin...
世紀の異種格闘技戦のゴングが
今 鳴らさ…
at the sound of the bel—
Begin!
始め！
Supreme!
究極！
Whoa, and there's his special
high-speed "no-motion" tackle!
（司会）おっと！　得意の
超高速ノーモーションタックル！
Chihiro Special #2—
チヒロスペシャル２…
（たたきつける音）
グワッ！
If this were sumo, you would have just died.
（火ノ丸）
これが相撲なら あんた 今死んだぜ
If we're equating losing with dying,
then, to us, this would be fatal.
敗北を死と捉えるなら
これが ワシらにとっての死
Still think it's a wimpy sport?
どうじゃ？　ぬるいか？
（歓声）
（司会）なんと 挑戦者
What a challenger!
He made a mockery of the
national champ's signature tackle!
国体王者の必殺タックルを
押しつぶした！
Stand up.
立てよ
In wrestling, you're not dead yet, right?
レスリングは…
お前は まだ死んどらんのじゃろう
（千比路）ンッ…　これが死？
This is death? I've got
lots of fight left in me.
俺は まだピンピンしてるぜ
If you want to kill me,
俺を殺したきゃ
首でも へし折れってんだ！
you'll have to break my neck!
He's blocking this, too?
これも防ぐかよ　なら—
In that case...
Low-flying airplane throw!
低空飛行機投げ
Chihiro Special #4!
チヒロスペシャル４号！
The champion's unleashing brutal
attacks, one after another!
（司会）
矢継ぎ早に繰り出される王者の猛攻
But instead of toppling his opponent,
he can't even drop him to his knees!
しかし 倒すどころか
膝をつかせることさえ かなわない
Come on, Kunisaki. How can
you be having this much trouble?
（礼奈）
ちょっと國崎　なに苦戦してんのよ
Incredible.
すげえ…
In sumo, if you fall, you lose.
相撲は倒れたら 即負け
That's why...
なので
倒れないということに関して—
You won't find anyone more resistant
to falling than a sumo wrestler.
相撲取りの右に出る者はいません！
We divide our attention between
standing and ground moves,
俺らが寝技に費やす時間も—
ひたすら
立ち技に明け暮れてるってわけか
but they can dedicate all of theirs
to standing moves, huh?
Still...
…にしても
片足で ここまで残すかよ
How can he last so long on one leg?!
However, the challenger has been
on the back foot for the whole match...
しかし 今のところ
防戦一方の挑戦者ですが…
Oh, wow! A barrage of open-hand strikes!
（突く音）
（司会）おっと 突っ張りだ！
I just faced the boxing club
and the karate club!
さっきまで
ボクシング部や空手部とやってんだ
Pummeling me isn't going to beat me—
今更 打撃に ひるむか！
（千比路）ウウッ！
（小関）逆(さか)とったり！
An armbar throw counter!
The challenger is going on the attack!
一気に攻勢に転じる挑戦者
（火ノ丸）ンンッ！
（小関）今度は外小股(そとこまた)！
An over-thigh scooping body drop!
He keeps backing off
after getting me on the ground.
こいつ…
いちいち仕切り直しやがる
He insists on being a sumo wrestler
to the very end, huh?
あくまで てめえは相撲取りってか
He's underestimating me.
ナメやがって…
There's something
different about Kunisaki.
（礼奈）國崎の雰囲気が変わった
You're strong, Hinomaru.
（千比路）お前は強(つえ)えぜ 火ノ丸
But your silly obsession with sumo
and your refusal to stay on the attack
だが てめえの そのこだわり
追撃しないぬるさ
will be your undoing!
後悔させてやるよ！
I'm going to win!
決める！
これが俺のハイパーフルマックス…
This is me, redlining it to the max!
Chihiro
Special #1
Chihiro Special #1!
Chihiro
Special #1
He drew him in and slung
him over his shoulder!
巻き込みながらの一本背負い！？
That's an impressive technique.
いい技じゃ…　じゃが！
But...
No way.
ウソだろう？　この技まで…
He countered that technique, too?
今度は ワシの番じゃ！
Now, it's my turn!
Right underhand throw!
Right
Right und
Right under
Right underhand
Right underhand throw
Demon
Demon wheel!
Wheel
Demon
We don't fight for the
survival of our bodies,
ワシらが賭けとるのは
肉体の生死ではない
but for the survival of our spirit.
“心”の生死じゃ
When all of your power, pride,
and resolve is thwarted,
己の覚悟とプライドを乗せた
全身全霊が はじき返され—
and you see your opponent
still standing in the ring...
土俵に残った相手を
見上げれば 十分…
力士は死ぬのさ
That's a sumo wrestler's death.
I didn't think you'd counter that.
（千比路）あれを返されちゃな…
I could fight on, but I'm
too disappointed to stand.
体はピンピンしてるが
悔しくて立てねえや
I've lost!
俺の負けだ
Tennis
club
Volleyball
Join
the
soccer
club!
（歓声）
（司会）レスリング対相撲
In the contest of wrestling vs sumo,
a battle between combat sports,
世紀の異種格闘技戦を
制したのは—
Ushio Hinomaru from
the sumo club is the victor!
相撲部 潮火ノ丸だ〜！
（拍手と歓声）
Th-This can't be happening...
こ… こんなはずでは…
My plan was to make an unfair call...
こいつに不利なジャッジをして—
You touched it
負けさせるつもりだったのに！
...to make sure he lost!
He's the
winner!
You did it, Ushio!
（小関）やったな 潮！
（火ノ丸）ウヘヘッ…
（千比路）なあ
廻しって いくらぐらいするんだ？
Hey, how much do mawashi belts cost?
Why do you ask?
（火ノ丸）
そんなこと聞いて 何を…
You need to ask? Isn't it obvious?
（千比路）
何って そりゃ決まってんだろう
（千比路）相撲部に入るんだよ
（火ノ丸たち）えっ？
I'm joining the sumo club.
A-Are you sure?
（火ノ丸）い… いいんか？
（千比路）ああ
Yeah. The core strength to never fall.
倒れない足腰 相手を押し込む圧力
総合をやるうえでは欲しい力だ
The hand strength to
push back an opponent.
I'll really want those skills
when I'm a mixed martial artist.
And it's a sport that
a guy like you can love.
それに
お前ほどの男がホレ込む競技だ
My interest in sumo has
gone into the redline!
俺は もう興味ビンビンの
フルスロットルだぜ！
（火ノ丸）ウヘヘッ…　部長
（小関）ああ
Captain!
Yeah!
Glad to have you on board, Kunisaki Chihiro!
お前さんなら大歓迎じゃ
國崎千比路！
W-Wait, are you serious?
（礼奈）ちょ… ちょっと本気？
相撲よ　相撲なのよ
It's sumo! Sumo!
What's your problem?
（千比路）何だよ？　うるせえな
You got something against the sumo club?
お前
何か相撲部に恨みでもあんのか？
恨みですって？
そんな なまやさしいものじゃない
Something against it?
That doesn't even begin
to describe how I feel.
潮火ノ丸！
私は あんたを絶対に許さない！
Ushio Hinomaru, I will
never, ever forgive you!
（火ノ丸）えっ？
（礼奈）フン！
What did you do to her?
（千比路）
お前　あいつに何したんだ？
I have no idea.
（火ノ丸）さっぱり分からん
Your sumo wrestling was incredible!
（生徒）相撲 すごかったよ
Oh, thank you!
おう ありがとうよ！
どうじゃ？　相撲やってみんか？
Would you like to give it a try?
（生徒）
あっ ごめん　やるのは ちょっと…
Uh, sorry, I don't think it's for me.
（礼奈）フン！　ムダよ
It's no use.
悔しいのぅ
Well, that's disappointing.
Even with all those people watching,
we didn't inspire any of them.
あれだけ観客がいながら
１人の心も動かせんかった
I feel like I'm letting sumo down.
なんだか相撲に申し訳ねえや
E-Excuse me...
（蛍(けい)）あ… あの…
（３人）うん？
I-I-I-I'd like to... j-join the sumo club.
（蛍）すす… 相撲部に
は… 入りたいんですけど…
I was i-inspired by your fight!
（蛍）お… お２人の戦いに
感銘を受けました
And, Hinomaru-san,
sumo's really awesome, isn't it?
特に火ノ丸さん
相撲って すごいですね！
What's he doing? Is he an idiot?
なんでよ？　バカじゃないの？
There's something about
being in a sumo ring.
（佑真）土俵の上には何かがある
男を震わす何かがな
Something that stirs the hearts of men.
（礼奈）あっ 佑真
Yuma.
He glimpsed it when Kunisaki
fought that shrimp.
（佑真）
あいつは 國崎とチビの戦いに—
その何かを見たんだろう
What are you on about? Ever since Hinomaru
beat you, you've been acting strange!
（礼奈）何言ってるの？
火ノ丸にやられてから変よ！
また前みたいに 強かったころの
お兄ちゃんに戻ってよ！
Go back to being my strong big brother!
Go beat up that Hinomaru guy!
あいつを…
火ノ丸をぶっ飛ばしてよ！
Sorry, but I'm done
with beating people up.
（佑真）
悪いけど もうケンカはしねえ
I've decided to take up sumo to defeat him.
あのチビは
相撲で ぶっ飛ばすって決めたんだ
（礼奈）相撲？
Sumo?
I can't go into it halfheartedly.
（佑真）そのためには
ハンパじゃいられねえんだ
死にものぐるいで向かわねえと
追いつけない場所にいやがるからな
He's at a level I can't reach unless
I work feverishly to get there.
Is it really worth going to
all that trouble for him?
それだけの価値が
あいつにあるっていうの？
（佑真）気になるなら
その目で確かめりゃいい
If you want to know the answer
to that, just use your eyes.
We worked so hard yesterday,
but only got two new members.
（小関）昨日は あんなに
頑張ったのに 入ったのは２人か
It's too early to give up!
（火ノ丸）まだ諦めるのは早いぞ
After morning practice,
we'll hand out more flyers...
今日も朝練のあとに ビラ配り…
The club room is so clean, it's sparkling!
（小関）部室がピカピカになってる
You're late!
（佑真）遅(おせ)えぞ てめえら
（火ノ丸）あっ…
What are you doing here?
何しとるんじゃ？　こんな所で
You're the one who said I should come
if I wanted to know why I lost!
自分を負かしたもんが何なのか—
知りたきゃ来いっつったのは
てめえだろうが
P-Plus... losing doesn't sit well with me.
な… 何より
負けっぱなしは性に合わねえしな
I've made up my mind to beat you
and become the best in Japan!
てめえをぶっ倒して
俺が日本一になるって決めたんだよ
I-I'm saying I'll join the sumo club!
だ… だから 俺が
相撲部に入ってやるっつってんだ！
I have no objections, as long as
our captain accepts you.
ワシは まあ
部長がいいと言うなら…
（小関）
えっ？　あっ いや 俺は別に…
Oh, I don't...
Y-Yuma-san!
（小関）ゆ… 佑真さん
I'm sorry for my actions.
（佑真）今まで悪かった
I know this is a self-serving request, but...
虫のいい話だってのは
分かってんだけどよ
Let me learn sumo...
俺に相撲をやらせてくれ　頼む！
Please!
Just feeling that way is enough.
その気持ちだけで十分です
断る理由は ありませんよ
I have no reason to turn you away.
Well, ain't this a sight?
（千比路）へえ…　こりゃ意外
（小関）えっ？
（佑真）
お… お前ら　いつから そこに？
Y-You! How long have you been standing there?
Your little display was very entertaining.
（千比路）いやぁ　なんか
面白いことになってんなと思って…
A-Are you looking down on me?
て… てめえ ナメてんのか！
So you've got five members now.
（桐仁(きりひと)）５人そろったみたいだな
（佑真）うん？
うん？　何だ？　お前
Who are you?
Kirihito! You also attend this school?
桐仁！　お前も この学校に？
（桐仁）
ああ　お前が入るって聞いたからな
Yes. I came here because
I'd heard you'd enrolled here.
Ushio, is this a friend of yours?
（小関）
潮の知り合い？　じゃ 経験者？
Have you done sumo before, then?
You're joining the club, right?
（千比路）入部するんだろう？
Yes, but not as a member.
（桐仁）ええ
でも 部員としてじゃないです
It looks like you plan
to enter a tournament,
どうやら
大会に出るつもりのようですが—
but as you are now, you will almost
certainly lose in the first round.
今のあなたたちでは
初戦敗退が目に見えている
（小関たち）あっ…
（佑真）なんだと てめえ！
What did you say?!
He doesn't know who he's talking to.
（千比路）こいつ
俺のことを知らないようだな
（桐仁）でも 安心してください
（一同）うん？
But don't worry.
俺が あなたたちを
全国に連れてってあげますよ
I will take you to nationals.
Yuma-san...
（舟木）佑真さん…
（西郷）最近 ずっと あの調子だな
He's been acting like that a lot lately.
That stray cat!
あの野良猫…
What about it?
（西郷）
あいつが どうかしたのか？
Doesn't it look like it's
gained a lot of weight?
いや 最近 すげえ太ってねえ？
Churu Churu
なんでかな…　こいつ見てると—
I wonder why I feel like...
...I can't leave him on his own.
放っておけねえんだよな
Next Bout
“The Kusanagi Sword”
He feels guilty.
（舟木）罪悪感だな
（西郷）ああ…
Yeah.